checkout.com 2014-07-02

# Checkout - Online Payments

This Privacy Statement deals with information that a user may provide on the Checkout websites. For the purposes of this Statement, Checkout definition of 'user' encompasses merchants, affiliate members, partners, sales agents, sponsors, customers and cardholders and any other visitor who discloses information to the company. Checkout is committed to respecting the privacy of your personal information and wants to promote trust and confidence on the Internet. To that end, Checkout hereby outlines the type of information that is collected and tracked on this website and how Checkout uses this information in its business operations.

##### Collection of Information

Checkout collects information from its users in the following methods.

##### Registration

Checkout collects personally identifiable information on its users through the registration process (merchant account applications, reseller program application, agent program application and customer's purchase information) where the applicant is required to give some of the following contact information: company information, product information, technical information, credit card information, account executive name, telephone number, email address, address.

##### Ordering

In order to complete an application form or a customer information request, the user is required to provide Checkout with the following information: name, mailing address, shipping address, email address, phone number and credit card information. This information is used to complete the account application process, to complete the customer's information request and to verify the validity of a request.

##### Tracking

Users' Internet Protocol (IP) address is automatically received and collected when they visit some Checkout websites. Checkout also tracks information such as the domain name from which a user visits us, the pages a user requests, and the amount of time that a user spends on the site. From the IP address, Checkout can only determine the Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of user's point of connectivity. This information is used in the aggregate for statistical purposes.

##### Checkout no Spam Policy

Merchants or any third party working on their behalf shall not use the Checkout mail service and or its name to send unsolicited e-mail messages, including, without limitation, bulk commercial advertising or informational announcements ("spam"). In addition, Merchants or any third party working on their behalf shall not (a) send e-mail messages which are excessive and/or intended to harass or annoy others, (b) continue to send e-mail messages or USENET postings to a recipient who has indicated that he/she does not wish to receive them, (c) send e-mail messages with forged header information, or (d) send malicious e-mail messages or USENET postings, including, without limitation, "mailbombing."

##### Use of Information

##### Information Collected Through Tracking

The information that Checkout collects is used in the aggregate to obtain demographic information about the entire Checkout audience in order to improve service to its customers and merchants, to perform statistical analysis of the collective characteristics and behavior of its users. From this information, Checkout can measure overall patron demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Checkout domain and to analyze how and where to apply its resources. Checkout also uses the collected aggregate data to inform its sponsors of the number of visitors who have seen and "clicked" on their advertisements. Cookies are used to determine what particular content (e.g. advertising) users view, how long they view it, which content or sites that users link to, and which services members and visitors tend to use.

##### Information Collected Through Registration

Merchants' personal information is used to set up the merchant's account, to send the merchants updates, or changes to Checkout services. Checkout uses credit card information to fulfill the merchant account application process. Customers' personal and payment information is used to confirm the customer's identity and to provide information concerning the customer's online order. All queries are initiated by the customer, through his/her entering of personally identifiable data on www.checkout.com; serving as a customer service site.

##### Sharing of Information

Checkout uses commercially reasonable precautions to keep all disclosed personal information secure. Information collected through tracking and registration will not be shared or sold to third parties for any purpose except as provided in this Privacy Policy, any contract between Checkout and the user and/or without the user's expressed permission.

##### Financial Institutions

Checkout credit card transactions are handled by third-party financial institutions that receive the credit card number and other personal information in order to verify the validity of the credit card numbers and process the transactions.

##### Law Enforcement Investigations

Checkout may be required to disclose personal information when required by law wherein it believes that such disclosure is necessary to comply with legal proceedings. Checkout responds to subpoenas, warrants, or other court orders regarding information that is contained within our access logs concerning any merchant, user, customer or visitor. Checkout reserves the right to release information concerning any user who is believed to be in violation of contract, regulations, laws or guidelines, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. Checkout cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use its services for illegal activities. Checkout also reserves the right to report any deemed illegal activity by its users to law enforcement agencies.

##### Clients

In the event of an inquiry or a dispute by a customer, Checkout releases to customers information about the merchant, such as Customer Service Phone Line (if provided by the merchant), merchant's administrative contact information, and merchant's website.

##### Third Party

Checkout discloses information only to third parties who are business partners that provide intrinsic services (i.e. credit card companies) and who are required to treat the information with the same degree of care. Please note that Checkout website links to a wide variety of other websites, and Checkout is not accountable for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users. Please note that Checkout does not control the acts of its users, merchants, suppliers, etc. All users should be aware that, when they disclose personal information to third parties on or off the Checkout websites, the information may be collected and used to send that user unsolicited email. In the event that a customer encounters a Checkout merchant who is improperly collecting or using personal information, please contact Checkout immediately.

##### Security

Checkout uses commercially reasonable precautions, such as security software, physical security features and strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of its users' personal information; it is also committed to constantly improving its security measures as new technology is made available. Checkout works diligently to protect the safety of customers' online purchases and merchants' sensitive information by using authentication technology (certificates) and encryption technology (SSL). Our secure server software encrypts all personal information, including credit card information and/or social security number, which are transmitted over the Internet to and from Checkout websites.

##### Updating and Correcting Information

If you would like to view the information Checkout has collected about you, correct your information or opt not to consent to certain uses of your personal information, please contact your assigned account executive, who will assist you in this process. If you have questions or suggestions, we can be reached at:

Checkout Ltd  
1st Floor, 32 Wigmore Street  
London, W1U 2RP  
United Kingdom  
Attn: Privacy Officer 

##### Changes to the Privacy Statement

This Statement is subject to change as Checkout enhances its services and products, as well as being amended to maintain compliance with the applicable laws and regulations. Users who have a contract with Checkout will be notified of any changes and other users will be notified prior to collecting such information, as well as of changes to any other part of the business that Checkout deems appropriate for disclosure.

If Checkout intends to use personal information in a manner other than is stated at the time of collection, users will be notified and given the opportunity to consent to such a use.

##### Note

Users of Checkout websites must abide by the regulations and laws of their country of origin.

The provisions of payment services in Europe are regulated by the Payment Services Directive (PSD), a European Community law and by the Payment Services Regulation 2009 in the UK. Checkout Ltd., as a Payment Institution is authorised by the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) under the Payment Services Regulations 2009 for the provision of payment services. Register No. [584615](http://www.fsa.gov.uk/register/psdFirmRefSearch.do?firmRef=584615)

##### Key features of the regulation include:

  * Capital requirements & liquidity - Payment Institutions are required to maintain minimum levels of capital. There is an initial and continuous threshold of € 125,000 own funds. We must also hold sufficiently liquid assets to be able to honoured processed transactions and to meet our working capital requirements.
  * Float Management - There is a clear set of regulations on how we have to safeguard our customers funds and how we can invest the funds received in exchange for the payment services. In particular the PSD and PSD require authorised payment institutions to safeguard funds received from customers so that, if there is an insolvency event, the payment funds would be protected from other creditors' claims and can be repaid to customers.
  * Management & Vetting at Entry - The FCA must be satisfied that all individuals who are responsible for the management of the payment service are of good repute and possess appropriate knowledge and experience. The FCA is performing a "fit and proper test" on each member of Checkout Ltd senior management considering honesty, integrity, reputation, competence, capability and financial soundness.
  * Systems & Controls - Checkout Ltd must maintain organisational arrangements that are sufficient to minimise the risk of the loss or reduction of our customers funds or assets through fraud, misuse, negligence or poor administration. In addition we are required to have effective risk management procedures, adequate internal control mechanisms and to maintain relevant records.
  * Financial Crime - Checkout Ltd must comply with legal requirements to deter and detect financial crime, which includes money laundering and terrorist financing. Relevant legislation includes the financial crime provisions in the EMRs, section 21A of the Terrorism Act 2000, the Proceeds of Crime Act 2002, the Money Laundering Regulations 2007, the EC wire transfer regulation21 and Schedule 7 to the Counter-Terrorism Act 2008. Authorised Payment Institutions are also subject to the various pieces of legislation that implement the UK's financial sanctions regime.

The Money Laundering Regulations 2007 require firms to put preventative measures in place. They require firms to ensure that they know their customers (including conducting customer identification and verification and undertake ongoing monitoring where applicable), to keep records of identity and to train their staff on the requirements of the Regulations. A senior member of staff needs to be appointed to oversee appropriate policies and procedures.

Checkout FCA Payment Institution registration: 584615

As a registered payment institution operating in UK and in the European Economic Area (EEA), Checkout Ltd. is subject to the Money Laundering Regulations 2007, the European Commissions (EC) Wire Transfer/Payment Regulations and the Counter-Terrorism Act 2008 (UK AML/CTF legislation framework).

Supervised by the FCA, Checkout Ltd. must meet the following Joint Money Laundering Steering Group (JMLSG) requirements:

  * Understand and interpret the legal and regulatory framework for AML/CTF requirements and systems
  * Understand standard industry best practice in AML/CTF procedures and proportionate risk- based approach
  * Design and implement the systems and controls necessary to mitigate the risk of being used in connection with money laundering or financing terrorism

Checkout Ltd's Legal Responsibilities

  * Verify customers' (including beneficial owners) identity and address.
  * Keep full records of all transactions together with identification provided.
  * Monitor any unusual or suspicious transactions of any size.
  * Legal obligation to report to the Serious Organised Crime Agency (SOCA) any suspicious transaction.

The information contained in this website is for general information purposes only. The information is provided by Checkout Ltd who endeavour to keep the information up to date and correct, however Checkout LTD make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability with respect to the website or the information, products, services, or related graphics contained on the website for any purpose. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk.

In no event will Checkout Ltd be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website.

Through this website you are able to link to other websites which are not under the control of Checkout Ltd. Checkout Ltd have no control over the nature, content and availability of those sites. The inclusion of any links does not necessarily imply a recommendation or endorse the views expressed within them.

Every effort is made to keep the website up and running smoothly. However, Checkout Ltd takes no responsibility for, and will not be liable for, the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond their control.

Goods and services offered by Checkout.com Merchants are not provided by a person or entity, run by WebMoney Transfer System. Checkout.com hereby acts as an independent entity providing services and making independent decisions on pricing and offers. Checkout.com Merchants, running WebMoney Transfer System do not receive any commission, interest fees or any other award or refund for the provided goods or services and are not liable for Checkout.com activities.

Verification, performed by WebMoney Transfer System only confirms the accuracy of Checkout.com Contact Details and proves Checkout.com identity. Verification is performed by Checkout.com own free will and doesn't mean or show Checkout.com connection to the commercial activity of WebMoney Transfer System Operators.

© Checkout Ltd 2013.  
Authorised and regulated as a Payment Institution by the UK Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) with reference [584615](http://www.fsa.gov.uk/register/psdFirmRefSearch.do?firmRef=584615).
